<text>
	<title>In-Game Rules</title>
	<info>
		<short>Click on a rule to see its full text. Use the scrollbar on the right in order to view additional rules.
		</short>
	</info>
	<rule>
		<short>Do not SPAM. </short>
		<long>SPAM means, in this context, either advertising something multiple times, or simply repeat the same message (or lack of message (such as empty spaces)) over and over, flooding people's screen.</long>
	</rule>
	<rule>
		<short>No prophanity or sexual references...</short>
		<long>Do NOT use profanity or sexual references on the channels or local talk, unless the channel number is over 100, or is 11 (11 is the flaming channel).</long>
	</rule>
	<rule>
		<short>Do not insult people</short>
		<long>Unless you have their consent, and it's not in a populated area.</long>
	</rule>
	<rule>
		<short>Do not swear</short>
		<long>Some vulgar language is allowed, if not used too much. For example, saying "FU CK YOU ALL" is not permited, but saying something like; "Fuck, that goblin pawned me" is acceptable, unless you spam, and as stated above, it's not to be used on the first channels. Use common sense.</long>
	</rule>
	<rule>
		<short>Do NOT block resources</short>
		<long>(such as ships, doors, bridges etc.) This is VERY bad, and if you do it, you get banned instantly.</long>
	</rule>
	<rule>
		<short>Do not use macroing/scripting/automate</short>
		<long>This is very annoying, and it will most likely get you banned, if we discover it.</long>
	</rule>
	<rule>
		<short>No offtopic chat in newbie and trade channel</short>
		<long>Only SOME offtopic chat in the newbie channel and marketing channel will be allowed. Marketing channel is much stricter then the newbie channel. The general chat is channel 4.</long>
	</rule>
	<rule>
		<short>Do NOT harass people.</short>
		<long></long>
	</rule>
	<rule>
		<short>No multiple accounts on at the same time, that help each other. </short>
		<long>That is, it's OK to have two characters online, if one stays and does nothing, or does something totally different than the other, and they don't interact (trade, exchanging items, train on each other, etc.). Doing so can make you lose your characters and even get you banned.</long>
	</rule>
	<rule>
		<short>No obscene names, no attempts to impersonate some staff member, no offensive names</short>
		<long>Also no utterly stupid spam names such as 0000000000 or AAAAAAAAA, etc. No characters whose sole purpose is their name (i.e. "runescape_is_cool" or "I_{love,hate}_[person's name]"). No spaming character creations by creating a lot of characters with similar names, or creating a lot of characters in a short period of time.</long>
	</rule>
	<rule>
		<short>No racism.</short> 
		<long>If you want to have a CIVILISED talk about races and such that is permited, but plain, offensive racism, only for the sake of annoying people is not tolerated.</long>
	</rule>
	<rule>
		<short>Do not lie to or scam the newbies. </short>
		<long>That includes giving false or inaccurate information in order to either directly profit from it, or alienate them from the game.</long>
	</rule>
	<rule>
		<short>No bag spamming</short>
		<long>Massively dropping bags to cause other bags to dissapear (some sort of DoS attack) is NOT allowed.</long>
	</rule>
	<rule>
		<short>Do not hack other accounts</short>
		<long>No attempts to hack other users, by distributing or advertising keylogers, trojans, etc.</long>
	</rule>
	<rule>
		<short>Bots must be declared</short>
		<long>All bots must be declared in this section of the forums, and follow the rules there: http://www.eternal-lands.com/forum/index.php?showtopic=7234</long>
	</rule>
	<rule>
		<short>Do not summon a lot of creatures near storages in the game</short>
		<long>As it causes lag and is annoying for other players. Also do not bring your summoned creatures near the storage. If a moderator/newbie helper tells you to leave the area because you are summoning then please do so. Do not summon a lot of creatures at the start point, where newbies come in.</long>
	</rule>
	<rule>
		<short>Don't be a troublemaker</short>
		<long>Don't cause problems on purpose that require the attentions of the mods.</long>
	</rule>
	<rule>
		<short>Don't exploit bugs.</short> 
		<long>Instead they need to be reported so that we can improve the game for everyone.</long>
	</rule>
	<rule>
		<short>Only publically sell in-game items &amp; services.</short> 
		<long>Do not sell items from other games, such as Runescape, on the channels, or  in public crowds, and do not constantly yell it out loud to other players around you. If you want to sell/trade stuff like that, then do it quietly with your friends. Otherwise it is an annoyance and considered spamming.</long>
	</rule>
	<rule>
		<short>No impersonating Moderators or other Players.</short>
		<long>Creating a character with a very similar name as someone else in the game and pretending to be them is not allowed.</long>
	</rule>	
	<info>
		<short>The rules might change in the future, and they are not carved in stone.</short>
	</info>
	<info>
		<short>Breaking the rules or the spirit of the rules can get you banned!</short>
		<long>Breaking these rules or the spirit of the rules (not just the letter of the law) can get you muted, banned, or other mod punishments depending on the judgement of any of the mods (including NH's). The higher the level a mod is that has to deal with you, the higher your punishment can be.</long>
	</info>
</text>
