<skills>
<Page Name="newskills">

	<size>Big</size>
	<color r="0" g="1" b="0"/>
	<Text>             Eternal Lands Help</Text><nl/>
	<Text>                   Skills</Text><nl/>

	<nl/>
	<size>Medium</size>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<size>Big</size>
	<text>           How do I start a skill?</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<size>Medium</size>
	<Text>                         </Text><link ref="fight" title=" Fighting "/><nl/>
	<size>Small</size>
	<nl/>
	<size>Medium</size>
	<Text>                        </Text><link ref="harv" title=" Harvesting "/><nl/>
	<size>Small</size>
	<nl/>
	<size>Medium</size>
	<Text>                       </Text><link ref="manu" title=" Manufacturing "/><nl/>
	<size>Small</size>
	<nl/>
	<size>Medium</size>
	<Text>                          </Text><link ref="alch" title=" Alchemy "/><nl/>
	<size>Small</size>
	<nl/>
	<size>Medium</size>
	<Text>                           </Text><link ref="magc" title=" Magic "/><nl/>
	<size>Small</size>
	<nl/>
	<size>Medium</size>
	<Text>                         </Text><link ref="pots" title=" Potioning "/><nl/>
	<size>Small</size>
	<nl/>
	<size>Medium</size>
	<Text>                         </Text><link ref="summ" title=" Summoning "/><nl/>
	<size>Small</size>
	<nl/>
	<size>Medium</size>
	<Text>                         </Text><link ref="crft" title=" Crafting "/><nl/>
	<size>Small</size>
	
	
</Page>


<Page Name="fight">
	<size>Big</size>
	<color r="0" g="1" b="0"/>
	<Text>           Eternal Lands Help</Text><nl/>
	<Text>                 Skills</Text><nl/>
	
	<size>Small</size>
	<color>yellow</color>
	<Text>                                                       </Text>
	<link ref="newskills" title="Back"/><nl/>	
	
	<nl/>
	<size>Big</size>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<Text>Fighting:</Text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	
	<size>Small</size>
	<text>The </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>fighting skills are attack and defense. To start</text><nl/>
	<text>raising these skills, you must fight a lot. You can fight</text><nl/>
	<text>with animals like rabbits, beavers, rats, deer and such,</text><nl/>
	<text>and later monsters like goblins, skeletons, etc. Another</text><nl/>
	<text>option is going onto special PK (player killing) maps</text><nl/>
	<text>and fighting other players.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>Beginners </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>should try to fight some of the weaker</text><nl/>
	<text>creatures in this game such as rabbits, rats, and</text><nl/>
	<text>beavers.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>While </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>fighting you get injured or sometimes killed. To</text><nl/>
	<text>regain health, make sure that your food level (the yellow</text><nl/>
	<text>bar) is positive. To do this you must eat. You can eat</text><nl/>
	<text>bread, fruits and veggies, and cooked meat. You can buy</text><nl/>
	<text>your food at the taverns, find it in bags on the ground</text><nl/>
	<text>on Isla Prima, or harvest the veggies yourself. You can</text><nl/>
	<text>eat it by clicking on the pointing finger icon at the</text><nl/>
	<text>bottom and then click on the food.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>To </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>heal even faster, you can buy or make healing potions</text><nl/>
	<text>and drink them. Another option is to cast healing spells</text><nl/>
	<text>on yourself.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>When </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>you are dead, you respawn near the campfire on Isla</text><nl/>
	<text>Prima. When your levels are a little higher, you are sent</text><nl/>
	<text>to the underworld. To leave the underworld, go north</text><nl/>
	<text>until you see large steps with candles on each side</text><nl/>
	<text>leading to a red glowing portal. Walk up close and click</text><nl/>
	<text>on it, that's the exit.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<nl/>
	
	<color>yellow</color>
	<text>                    </text>
	<link ref="newskills" title="Back To Help Index"/>
	<nl/>
</Page>


<Page Name="harv">
	<size>Big</size>
	<color r="0" g="1" b="0"/>
	<Text>           Eternal Lands Help</Text><nl/>
	<Text>                 Skills</Text><nl/>
	
	<size>Small</size>
	<color>yellow</color>
	<Text>                                                       </Text>
	<link ref="newskills" title="Back"/><nl/>	
	
	<nl/>
	<size>Big</size>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<Text>Harvesting:</Text><nl/>
	<nl/>

	<size>Small</size>
	<text>Harvesting </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>is used to get resources like flowers, ore,</text><nl/>
	<text>gems, food and such. To start this skill, simply find a</text><nl/>
	<text>flower and click on it and wait. You see a message "You</text><nl/>
	<text>started to harvest xxx" where xxx is the name of the</text><nl/>
	<text>flower you clicked on. Open your inventory with a click</text><nl/>
	<text>on the bag icon or press CTRL-i and you should see that</text><nl/>
	<text>you get more and more flowers.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>You </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>will get harvesting xp for 120 items maximum per</text><nl/>
	<text>ingame hour (to see what time it is ingame, click on the</text><nl/>
	<text>clock on the right of your screen). A red message tells</text><nl/>
	<text>you when you have reached this limit. You can, of course,</text><nl/>
	<text>continue harvesting to get items, but you won't get any</text><nl/>
	<text>harvesting xp for those.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>While </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>harvesting different kinds of flowers you may find</text><nl/>
	<text>out that you get a different amount of harvesting xp for</text><nl/>
	<text>each flower type. Items that are hard to get, give more</text><nl/>
	<text>xp than items that are easy to get. For beginners it's</text><nl/>
	<text>vegetables to harvest. It will take longer than flowers,</text><nl/>
	<text>but vegetables give the best harvesting xp. An extra</text><nl/>
	<text>benefit to harvesting vegetables is that it is food. No</text><nl/>
	<text>need to buy it anymore. And vegetables are a source of</text><nl/>
	<text>money, because you can sell them to taverns.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>There </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>are also harvesting events which may occur from</text><nl/>
	<text>time to time. Some effect you negatively, some</text><nl/>
	<text>positively. For example, you can get stung by a bee</text><nl/>
	<text>(losing health), the Queen of Nature blesses you with</text><nl/>
	<text>extra harvesting xp, or you find a bag with a few gold</text><nl/>
	<text>coins. These events stop the autoharvester. You must</text><nl/>
	<text>start harvesting again by clicking on the resource you</text><nl/>
	<text>want to harvest.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>To </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>stop harvesting, click again on the resource you are</text><nl/>
	<text>harvesting or simply walk away.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<nl/>
	
	<color>yellow</color>
	<text>                    </text>
	<link ref="newskills" title="Back To Help Index"/>
	<nl/>
</Page>

	
<Page Name="manu">
	<size>Big</size>
	<color r="0" g="1" b="0"/>
	<Text>           Eternal Lands Help</Text><nl/>
	<Text>                 Skills</Text><nl/>
	
	<size>Small</size>
	<color>yellow</color>
	<Text>                                                       </Text>
	<link ref="newskills" title="Back"/><nl/>	
	
	<nl/>
	<size>Big</size>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>Manufacturing:</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	
	<size>Small</size>
	<text>To </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>start making items, you need a needle, thread, and</text><nl/>
	<text>furs. While hunting rabbits, keep the furs and sell only</text><nl/>
	<text>the meat. Then go to a General Store, Lakeside has one</text><nl/>
	<text>for example, and buy some thread and one needle.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>Lakeside </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>is the village at the docks on Whitestone map.</text><nl/>
	<text>To go there from Isla Prima, go south to the docks and</text><nl/>
	<text>click on the flag on the ship. Press TAB key to see a</text><nl/>
	<text>map. General Stores are the green dots on it.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>Make </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>sure you have food in your inventory. You can't</text><nl/>
	<text>manufacture when you are hungry (yellow bar below 0) so</text><nl/>
	<text>keep your food level positive.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>The </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>first thing to make is warm fur gloves. You need 3</text><nl/>
	<text>brown rabbit furs and 2 thread. Make sure that you have</text><nl/>
	<text>the needle in your inventory too. Open the manufacturing</text><nl/>
	<text>window by clicking on the "hammer and anvil" icon on the</text><nl/>
	<text>bottom. Then click 3 times on the rabbit furs, 2 times on</text><nl/>
	<text>the thread. Now click the "Mix" button and wait. And,</text><nl/>
	<text>hopefully, you have made your first pair of fur gloves.</text><nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>**Note**: </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>You will sometimes fail to make an item. This</text><nl/>
	<text>is normal. Just try again. Now make as many fur gloves as</text><nl/>
	<text>you can get rabbit furs until your manufacture level is</text><nl/>
	<text>up to 4 or 5. You can sell the gloves to any General</text><nl/>
	<text>Store to make some money.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>Now </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>it's time to make yourself a fur hat. Go on the</text><nl/>
	<text>Whitestone map and try to kill a white rabbit. Tirnwood</text><nl/>
	<text>Vale (click Tab to see where that is) is good place to</text><nl/>
	<text>find white rabbits. You will also need to get 3 beaver</text><nl/>
	<text>furs, you can find beavers on Isla Prima. Then all you</text><nl/>
	<text>need to do is buy 3 threads and you have the ingredients</text><nl/>
	<text>for "teh one hat".</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>To </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>make the hat, be sure that you have the needle in your</text><nl/>
	<text>inventory, then open the manufacturing window(hammer and</text><nl/>
	<text>anvil icon) and click 3 times on the beaver furs, 3 times</text><nl/>
	<text>on the thread and 1 time on the white rabbit fur. Then</text><nl/>
	<text>click "Mix" button, wait, and pray that you have now made</text><nl/>
	<text>a fur hat.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>When </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>you can make fur hats easily, try to get some wolf</text><nl/>
	<text>and fox furs. Ask players who are training(fighting) on</text><nl/>
	<text>foxes or wolfs if they can sell you a few furs. Of course</text><nl/>
	<text>you can try to kill some wolves and foxes yourself, but</text><nl/>
	<text>they are much harder to kill than rabbits or rats, so</text><nl/>
	<text>instead of committing suicide, better ask other players</text><nl/>
	<text>for furs.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>You </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>need 3 wolf furs, 2 fox furs, and 5 thread to make a</text><nl/>
	<text>fur cloak. Don't forget you need your needle and food in</text><nl/>
	<text>your inventory as well. Follow the same procedure as</text><nl/>
	<text>above to start to make the cloak.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>And </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>now your set of fur clothes is complete; gloves, hat,</text><nl/>
	<text>and cloak.</text><nl/>
	<text>Now you can wear them. Congratulations!</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>The </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>next useful things to make are leather gloves. You</text><nl/>
	<text>need 4 leather and 4 thread. Leather can be bought at</text><nl/>
	<text>General Stores. Have your needle in your inventory and</text><nl/>
	<text>eat some food, open the manufacture window, click 4 times</text><nl/>
	<text>on leather, 4 times on thread and then the "Mix" button.</text><nl/>
	<text>Expect to fail and even loose the ingredients. After a</text><nl/>
	<text>few tries, you should now have a leather glove, which is</text><nl/>
	<text>very useful. Leather gloves are needed to harvest sulfur,</text><nl/>
	<text>pick cactus, and you can even use it as a weapon!</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<nl/>
	
	<color>yellow</color>
	<text>                    </text>
	<link ref="newskills" title="Back To Help Index"/>
	<nl/>
</Page>

	
<Page Name="alch">
	<size>Big</size>
	<color r="0" g="1" b="0"/>
	<Text>           Eternal Lands Help</Text><nl/>
	<Text>                 Skills</Text><nl/>
	
	<size>Small</size>
	<color>yellow</color>
	<Text>                                                       </Text>
	<link ref="newskills" title="Back"/><nl/>	
	
	<nl/>
	<size>Big</size>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>Alchemy:</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<size>Small</size>
	<text>Alchemy </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>is the art of making essences and metal bars. So</text><nl/>
	<text>let's make fire essences to start out with, they are easy</text><nl/>
	<text>to make and you can sell them to magic shops or players</text><nl/>
	<text>to make money.</text><nl/>
	<text>Fire essences are used for metal smelting, to make metal</text><nl/>
	<text>bars and other metal stuff.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>You </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>need sulfur, red roses, and red snapdragons to make a</text><nl/>
	<text>fire essence. Both flowers can be found on the Valley of</text><nl/>
	<text>the Dwarves map, on the eastern side of the river hidden</text><nl/>
	<text>in the woods(you might have to search for them a bit).</text><nl/>
	<text>To go to the Valley of the Dwarves from Isla Prima, go</text><nl/>
	<text>south to the docks, click on the flag on the ship. Now</text><nl/>
	<text>you are at the Lakeside docks. Go to the second ship ,</text><nl/>
	<text>click on the flag (has a deer on it) and you are at the</text><nl/>
	<text>docks of Desert Pines. The second ship (has a bear on the</text><nl/>
	<text>flag) brings you to the Valley of the Dwarves. Harvest</text><nl/>
	<text>the flowers and store them at Molgor, the storage in the</text><nl/>
	<text>town.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>Sulfur </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>can be found in Crystal Caves in the middle of the</text><nl/>
	<text>Desert Pines map. To go there from the Valley of the</text><nl/>
	<text>Dwarves, go back to the docks, click on the flag with the</text><nl/>
	<text>deer on it. The cave is located in the mountains in the</text><nl/>
	<text>middle of the map. This cave is huge, browse some</text><nl/>
	<text>helpsites like "EL Guide" for a map or the cave, sulfur</text><nl/>
	<text>are the yellow dots. To harvest sulfur, you must wear</text><nl/>
	<text>leather gloves. Read the manufacture walkthrough how to</text><nl/>
	<text>make some, or you can buy them from the Whitestone City</text><nl/>
	<text>blacksmith (purple dot), or buy them from other players.</text><nl/>
	<text>Once you find and harvest the sulfur, you can store it at</text><nl/>
	<text>the Desert Pines storage npc named Grim.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>Now </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>that you have stored the flowers and sulfur, get some</text><nl/>
	<text>food to have in your inventory. Go back to Grim and</text><nl/>
	<text>withdraw 10 red roses, 10 red snapdragons and 10 sulfur.</text><nl/>
	<text>Make sure that you're not hungry because you can't make</text><nl/>
	<text>essences when your food level is not positive. Open the</text><nl/>
	<text>manufacturing window (hammer and anvil icon at the</text><nl/>
	<text>bottom) and click on one rose, one snapdragon and one</text><nl/>
	<text>sulfur. Then click the "Mix" button and wait. And</text><nl/>
	<text>hopefully you'll have made your first fire essence. It's</text><nl/>
	<text>possible to fail, if that happens just try again.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>Now </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>make some more fire essences. When you are done,</text><nl/>
	<text>search for the magic shops in Grahms Village(west of the</text><nl/>
	<text>tavern) or in Whitestone City on the Whitestone/Lakeside</text><nl/>
	<text>map. Enter and sell them and you now know how to make</text><nl/>
	<text>easy money.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>Now </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>start to make tons of fire essences. Look very</text><nl/>
	<text>carefully at your inventory. If there is suddenly a</text><nl/>
	<text>second box with a fire essence, that does not mean that</text><nl/>
	<text>the first box is full. Check both essences with the "eye"</text><nl/>
	<text>cursor (click on the "eye" icon at the bottom) to find</text><nl/>
	<text>out what they are. One of them is an enriched fire</text><nl/>
	<text>essence and can be sold to players for BIG amount of</text><nl/>
	<text>money. There is a very small chance to make an enriched</text><nl/>
	<text>essence, so if you get one, you are really really lucky!</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<nl/>
	
	<color>yellow</color>
	<text>                    </text>
	<link ref="newskills" title="Back To Help Index"/>
	<nl/>
</Page>


<Page Name="magc">
	<size>Big</size>
	<color r="0" g="1" b="0"/>
	<Text>           Eternal Lands Help</Text><nl/>
	<Text>                 Skills</Text><nl/>
	
	<size>Small</size>
	<color>yellow</color>
	<Text>                                                       </Text>
	<link ref="newskills" title="Back"/><nl/>	
	
	<nl/>
	<size>Big</size>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>Magic:</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<size>Small</size>
	<text>Magic </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>is the art of casting spells. To do so, you need</text><nl/>
	<text>sigils and essences. You can buy sigils in magic shops on</text><nl/>
	<text>the Whitestone map. Once you have bought a sigil, it</text><nl/>
	<text>shows up in your magic window (click on the icon with the</text><nl/>
	<text>magic wand), not in your inventory, and stays forever.</text><nl/>
	<text>Essences can be bought at magic shops too, but they are</text><nl/>
	<text>single use. You can also make your own essences using</text><nl/>
	<text>alchemy or buy them from other players.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>To </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>start with magic, go to the magic shop in Grahms</text><nl/>
	<text>Village and buy the "Health" sigil. Then find the magic</text><nl/>
	<text>shop in Whitestone City and get the "Increase" sigil.</text><nl/>
	<text>There you should buy a few health essences too. And now</text><nl/>
	<text>you are ready to cast heal spells. So fight some animals</text><nl/>
	<text>to get injured and heal yourself!</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>Now </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>click on the icon with the magic wand at the bottom</text><nl/>
	<text>and you should see the 2 sigils. First click on the</text><nl/>
	<text>Increase sigil, then on the Health sigil. Make sure that</text><nl/>
	<text>you have the health essences in your inventory, then</text><nl/>
	<text>click the "Cast" button. If you don't fail, you should</text><nl/>
	<text>have recovered 5 material points now (red bar). And you</text><nl/>
	<text>lost 5 ethereal points (blue bar). Each spell uses a</text><nl/>
	<text>certain amount of ethereal points (also known as "mana").</text><nl/>
	<text>When your ethereal points are less than 5, you can't</text><nl/>
	<text>cast the heal spell, you must wait, until you have</text><nl/>
	<text>regenerated more ethereal points. This also needs a</text><nl/>
	<text>positive food level.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>You </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>can also drink mana potions or potions of spirit</text><nl/>
	<text>restauration to regain Ethereal points. Mira, the potion</text><nl/>
	<text>seller in the market place in Whitestone City, sells</text><nl/>
	<text>them, or you can buy them from other players who can make</text><nl/>
	<text>them. To train magic, just go and buy the cheap mana</text><nl/>
	<text>potions, cast spells, then drink the potions when your</text><nl/>
	<text>mana points are too low to cast any more spells. That's a</text><nl/>
	<text>nice way to train magic. And make sure to keep your</text><nl/>
	<text>empty vials, you will need them later!</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<nl/>
	
	<color>yellow</color>
	<text>                    </text>
	<link ref="newskills" title="Back To Help Index"/>
	<nl/>
</Page>



<Page Name="pots">
	<size>Big</size>
	<color r="0" g="1" b="0"/>
	<Text>           Eternal Lands Help</Text><nl/>
	<Text>                 Skills</Text><nl/>
	
	<size>Small</size>
	<color>yellow</color>
	<Text>                                                       </Text>
	<link ref="newskills" title="Back"/><nl/>	
	
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<size>Big</size>
	<text>Potions</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<size>Small</size>
	<text>Lets </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>start with making healing potions. When you drink</text><nl/>
	<text>them, you regain 5 material points (red bar), so you can</text><nl/>
	<text>use then when fighting creatures.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>To </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>make all potions, you need empty vials. The easiest</text><nl/>
	<text>way to get some, is to buy mana potions from Mira, the</text><nl/>
	<text>potion seller in Whitestone City market place. She</text><nl/>
	<text>charges 5 gold coins per mana potion, so buy some and</text><nl/>
	<text>drink them to get some empty vials.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>Then </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>go back to Grahm's Village, to the western most</text><nl/>
	<text>house with the vegetable patch in the garden. Near the</text><nl/>
	<text>house are sunflowers, pick a few and pick some vegetables</text><nl/>
	<text>as well. After that, buy some wine from the Tavern and</text><nl/>
	<text>you are ready to make potions.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>Make </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>sure that your food level is positive, then open the</text><nl/>
	<text>manufacturing window by clicking on the hammer and anvil</text><nl/>
	<text>icon at the bottom. Click once on a vial, wine and</text><nl/>
	<text>sunflower. Click the "Mix" button and wait. If you don't</text><nl/>
	<text>fail, you will have your first self-made healing potion.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<nl/>
	
	<color>yellow</color>
	<text>                    </text>
	<link ref="newskills" title="Back To Help Index"/>
	<nl/>
</Page>



<Page Name="summ">
	<size>Big</size>
	<color r="0" g="1" b="0"/>
	<Text>           Eternal Lands Help</Text><nl/>
	<Text>                 Skills</Text><nl/>
	
	<size>Small</size>
	<color>yellow</color>
	<Text>                                                       </Text>
	<link ref="newskills" title="Back"/><nl/>	
	
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<size>Big</size>
	<text>Summoning</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<size>Small</size>
	<text>Summoning </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>lets you bring creatures to life in this world</text><nl/>
	<text>for a limited time. They will follow you wherever you go</text><nl/>
	<text>on the actual map until they die.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>First, </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>you need a dead rabbit. Just go and kill one. You</text><nl/>
	<text>need 1 brown rabbit fur, 1 bone and 1 meat. Buy a life</text><nl/>
	<text>essence in one of the magic shops, make sure that your</text><nl/>
	<text>ethereal points are not 0 (blue bar) and that's it. Now</text><nl/>
	<text>find a quiet place. Never summon at crowded places like</text><nl/>
	<text>storages and beam/wraith.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>Open </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>the manufacture window by clicking on the hammer and</text><nl/>
	<text>anvil icon at the bottom. Click once on the brown rabbit</text><nl/>
	<text>fur, the meat, the bone and the life essence. Now click</text><nl/>
	<text>the "Mix" button and wait. If you dont fail, there is now</text><nl/>
	<text>a rabbit hopping near you. Now walk away and it will</text><nl/>
	<text>follow you.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<nl/>
	
	<color>yellow</color>
	<text>                    </text>
	<link ref="newskills" title="Back To Help Index"/>
	<nl/>
</Page>



<Page Name="crft">
	<size>Big</size>
	<color r="0" g="1" b="0"/>
	<Text>           Eternal Lands Help</Text><nl/>
	<Text>                 Skills</Text><nl/>
	
	<size>Small</size>
	<color>yellow</color>
	<Text>                                                       </Text>
	<link ref="newskills" title="Back"/><nl/>	
	
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<size>Big</size>
	<text>Crafting</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	
	<size>Small</size>
	
	<text>To </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>start crafting, you need a lot of knowledge. Meaning</text><nl/>
	<text>you must read books first before you can start. Go to</text><nl/>
	<text>Tarsengaard and enter the magic school. But beware of the</text><nl/>
	<text>armored goblin on that map! You can enter Tarsengaard</text><nl/>
	<text>both from The Valley of the Dwarves or from the</text><nl/>
	<text>Whitestone maps. Find Itilli in the registry room, that's</text><nl/>
	<text>on the left hand side just after entering the entrance</text><nl/>
	<text>hall. Buy from her the Generic Rings and Gold Rings books</text><nl/>
	<text>and read them. Yes, you will start with making simple</text><nl/>
	<text>gold rings.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>While </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>reading, make sure, that your artificial nexus is 1</text><nl/>
	<text>(see Wraith). Then go and get some gold bars, make them</text><nl/>
	<text>(alchemy) or buy them from other players. You will also</text><nl/>
	<text>need some fire essences. Make them (alchemy) or buy them</text><nl/>
	<text>from other players or magic shops on the Whitestone map.</text><nl/>
	<text>And last you need a ring mold. The magic shop in Portland</text><nl/>
	<text>(yellow dot on map) sells it. There you can get some</text><nl/>
	<text>other items needed for crafting too like gem sanders, gem</text><nl/>
	<text>cutters and such.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>When </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>you are done reading both books, have the gold bars,</text><nl/>
	<text>fire essences, and ring mold in your inventory, you are</text><nl/>
	<text>ready to start. Don't forget to grab some food.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<color r="1" g="0.3" b="1"/>
	<text>Now </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>open the manufacture window (the icon with the hammer</text><nl/>
	<text>and anvil at the bottom), click 2 times on a gold bar, 3</text><nl/>
	<text>times on a fire essence, and then click the "Mix"</text><nl/>
	<text>button. Wait, and hopefully you will have made your first</text><nl/>
	<text>gold ring. To make silver rings, go to Itilli and buy</text><nl/>
	<text>the Silver Rings book and read it. And so forth. The gold</text><nl/>
	<text>and silver rings you make now are ingredients in making</text><nl/>
	<text>the magic rings we use such as teleport rings, damage</text><nl/>
	<text>rings, and disengagement rings.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<text>As </text>
	<color r="0.0" g="0.5" b="1"/>
	<text>you now have found out, crafting is a very expensive</text><nl/>
	<text>and time consuming skill normally started by the more</text><nl/>
	<text>advanced players.</text><nl/>
	<nl/>
	<nl/>
	
	
	<color>yellow</color>
	<text>                    </text>
	<link ref="newskills" title="Back To Help Index"/>
	<nl/>
</Page>



</skills>

